safc.com 2016-06-09

# Privacy Policy - SAFC

Published: 17 August, 2012  
by Administrator 

**SAFC website information  
**This Website is owned and operated by Sunderland Association Football Club Limited ("SAFC"). ****

We are registered on the public register of data controllers maintained by the Information Commissioner. We are committed to protecting your privacy. We take our responsibilities to secure your personal information very seriously. Under the Data Protection Act 1998 ("DPA"), we follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of information, which you give to us.

Our Privacy Policy applies only to information that we obtain from you via the website located at [www.safc.com](http://www.safc.com/). In using the SAFC website, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information by SAFC in the ways set out in the Privacy Policy. If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy please contact [webmaster@safc.com](mailto:webmaster@safc.com).

If you visit a Website operated by a third party through a link included on this website, your information may be used differently by the operator of the linked website and a third party website may have different privacy and security policies. We do not have any control over any websites other than [www.safc.com](http://www.safc.com/) and take no responsibility for information given to any website other than [www.safc.com](http://www.safc.com/)

**Collecting information  
**When using this website you may encounter areas such as games, competitions, chat forums, shopping or video services where you may be asked to enter information about you. Such information will only be used for the purposes stated in this Privacy Policy. ****

By entering information about you, you accept that we may retain your information and that it may be held by us or any third party company, which processes it on our behalf.

You can [contact us by clicking here](http://www.safc.com/hygiene-pages/contact-us). Alternatively, you can write to us at the Sunderland Stadium of Light, Sunderland, Tyne & Wear SR5 1SU, England. Telephone number 0871 911 1200.

The information you provide to us when using this Website will be processed for the following reasons:-

• to handle orders, deliver products and/ or services;  
• to process payments;  
• to communicate with you about orders, products, services and promotional offers;  
• to update our records;  
• to administer and maintain your user account with us;  
• to process any request for advice or information supplied by us;  
• to notify you of our bulletins, information packs and services;  
• to customise this Website according to your interests;  
• to perform statistical analyses and assessments of the use of this Website;  
• to research our database;  
• to analyse our customer base;  
• to inform third party advertisers of the results of the statistical analyses of the use of their adverts on this Website (aggregated data only);  
• to comply with our statutory and regulatory obligations; [and]  
• to enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf.

The type of information we will collect about you includes:-

• your first name and your surname and your address;  
• your telephone number (in case we need to contact you urgently) and your email address;  
• your credit card details if you subscribe to one of our online services;  
• your occupation;  
• your interests;  
• the information included in any online services to which you subscribe;  
• details about the services you specifically request;  
• information you complete by way of our surveys;  
• your age and date of birth;

We do not keep your personal information any longer than is necessary.

By joining the SAFC email update service, and/ or as a supporter, customer, subscriber or competition entrant, we will occasionally email you with our latest news and information about our products, services, special offers, promotions and any other advertising or marketing materials which we think may be of interest to you.

For example, we will often give advance notice of our fantastic sales offers so that you can pick up a bargain. You will be asked when registering on the website to indicate if you do not want to be contacted by us in this way. You will need to provide us with your name and email address if you wish to subscribe to this service. 

Third party promotions **  
** We would also like to pass your details to third parties and organisations approved by us and with whom we have commercial links so that they may contact you to inform you about their products and/ or services and promotions, which may be of interest to you. We will only disclose your data to third parties if you consent to us doing so. You may be asked when registering on the website to indicate if you allow us to pass your details to any third parties. ****

You may refuse, at any time, any mailing or other marketing communication from us or require us, at any time, to cease to process your data for any particular purpose(s) and unsubscribe by writing to us at the above address or emailing us at [webmaster@safc.com](mailto:webmaster@safc.com).

Likewise, you may notify us of any updates, amendments and corrections to previously collected User information by emailing [webmaster@safc.com](mailto:webmaster@safc.com)

SAFC promotions   
When you enter a SAFC competition or take up a promotional offer, we may ask you for your name, address, and email address, so that we can administer the contest and notify winners.

We will never collect sensitive information about you without your explicit consent.

Any information that we collect about you is stored electronically on our database. It may also be printed and stored in our filing system.  
We will keep your personal information confidential except to the extent that we are compelled to disclose it by law (for example where fraud or other crime is involved) or to comply with an instruction of a regulatory body of a competent jurisdiction.

From time to time we may be called upon to demonstrate our maintenance of certain professional standards as set by appropriate authorities and/or to satisfy our auditors and/or to comply with regulations in relation to money laundering or other statutory requirements.

If you do not consent to our production of your details for this purpose only as an exception to our duty of confidentiality, you can let us know by emailing[webmaster@safc.com](mailto:webmaster@safc.com).

If you believe that the information we hold about you is inaccurate you may notify us of any amendments or corrections by writing to us at the above address or by sending us an e-mail at [webmaster@safc.com](mailto:webmaster@safc.com).

We are confident in our security. However, due to the nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee the protection of your personal information and we cannot be responsible for any outcomes resulting from a breach of security when the website is used.

Security is very important to us. Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") encryption technology is used by us for protection of information in transit for any sensitive transactions such as payments. Additional security procedures are in place to protect the confidentiality, integrity and availability of your user information.

As required by the Data Protection Act 1998, we follow strict security proceedings in the storage and disclosure of information, which you have given to us to prevent unauthorised access.

We have appointed an agent to collect credit card payments from you on our behalf. All credit card transactions conducted from this website are carried out over a secure link for your security.

By transmitting your credit card details, you agree to our agent using your details for the purposes of:-

a. authorising your credit card;  
b. debiting your credit card account for such of our goods you buy and/ or services you use; and  
c. advising us that payment has been made.

By registering to participate in one of our information rooms or forums you consent to the wider dissemination of the information you provide to the other participants in that information room or forum to achieve your joint objectives.

We reserve the right to appoint an Internet service provider to host our Website on our behalf which may be situated outside the European Economic Area. By agreeing to our terms and conditions of use of our Website you consent to any transfer of your personal information outside the European Economic Area. This may be necessary for us to achieve the purposes set out above.

You should be aware that countries outside the European Union may have a lower standard of protection for personal information than that required by the Data Protection Act 1998. If it is necessary to transfer your data to an organisation based outside the European Union we will make every effort to ensure that your personal data is processed in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, as implementing the EU Directive on the protection of personal data, and any other Act or Acts replacing or modifying such Act for the time being in force, through the implementation of an agreement ensuring adequate protection of your personal data.

**Site tracking & cookies**  
When visiting our website, we would like to use "cookies" and other tracking technologies which record information and data automatically.

What are cookies?  
"Cookies" are small text files stored on your "browser" on your computer's hard drive, which collect basic information, but not personally identifying information, that a website can use to recognize repeat site visits. Cookies send information stored on them back to our webserver when you access our website.

Cookies enable SAFC to provide features such as remembering your address, so that you do not have to re-enter it each time you use the website. Cookies do not attach to your system or damage your files.

Removing cookies  
Cookies can be deleted from your hard drive if you wish. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. You can usually change your browser so that it will not accept cookies. If you do this, you will still be able to browse around the site and use most of the features on the website but the functions that allow you to add items to your trolley, set up a new account or access an existing account will not be available. Alternatively, you can adjust your browser to tell you when a website tries to put a cookie on your computer. How you adjust your browser to stop it accepting cookies or to notify you of them will depend on the type of internet browser programme, which your computer uses.

If your computer uses Microsoft Internet Explorer or Netscape Navigator, you will need to follow these instructions at this link [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) (SAFC is not responsible for the content of external websites.)

Go to the heading "Manage Cookies". Click onto the option you prefer, either stopping cookies being installed or notifying you of them. From the list provided, click onto the programme, which your computer uses. If this is not shown on the list, click on the "help" heading on the bar at the top of this page, search for information on "cookies" - an explanation of how to delete cookies will appear, then follow those instructions.

If we cannot use such technology it is possible that certain functionality or 'personalised' services of this site might be affected and you might not be able to access certain Webpages. This information does not identify you personally.

What information do we collect?  
We automatically collect and store only the following information about your visit:-

• the internet domain and IP address from where you access our Website;  
• the type of browser software and operating system used to access our Website;  
• the date and time you access our Website;  
• the pages you enter, visit and exit our Website from; and  
• if you linked to our Website from another Website, the address of that Website.

Why do we collect this information?  
We use this information to help us identify click stream patterns, to compile aggregate data in order to observe behaviour and to improve our Website, to learn about the number of visitors to our Website, the types of technology our visitors use, to target the advertising and to assess the general effectiveness of such advertising.

We only use this information to ensure that our Webpages stay compatible with a selection of browsers and systems and thereby ensure that the pages appeal to a wide audience.

Currently our Webpages are optimised for the following Internet browsers: Internet Explorer 8.0+, Firefox, Safari, Chrome and native browsers on mobile devices and tablets.

We do not use cookies to collect or store personal information such as your name or email address.

**Third party advertising cookies**  
Some of the advertisements you see on this site are generated by third parties. Some of these third parties generate their own "anonymous cookies", for the same reasons we do: to track how many unique users have seen a particular ad, and how many times they have seen it.

These third party cookies cannot be used to identify an individual user, but only for statistical purposes, for example, in providing you with advertisements that are more relevant to your interests. Additionally, the companies that generate these cookies have their own, very strict, privacy policies but we don't have access to these cookies; other than allowing them to be served, we have no role to play in these cookies at all (although we may use statistical information arising from these third party cookies and provided to us by third parties, to improve the targeting of advertisements to users).

**Consent to cookies  
**In using this website, and by submitting your information, you consent to the collection, storage and use of your personal information by us as set out in this Policy. ****

If you do not agree, please leave this website now.

You may save this Privacy Policy onto your computer for future reference.

Should you wish to obtain a copy of the personal data that we hold on you, please send an e-mail to the following address: [webmaster@safc.com](mailto:webmaster@safc.com).

As soon as we are satisfied as to your identity, we will send to you, within 40 days, a copy of all the data that we hold concerning you.  
Any queries or comments about this privacy policy should be forwarded by email to [webmaster@safc.com](mailto:webmaster@safc.com).

If you have a complaint concerning any breach of this privacy policy, contact us by email at [webmaster@safc.com](mailto:webmaster@safc.com). When we receive the complaint, we will review it and ensure that we are in compliance with our privacy policy and all applicable laws. We will contact you within 40 days of receiving your complaint to inform you of the results of your complaint.

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and in what circumstances we disclose it.

List of performance cookies

**Cookie name**

| 

**Purpose**  
  
---|---  
  
Adtech.de

| 

The cookies from this domain are used for display advertising  
  
CFP

| 

This ADTECH cookie allows the ad server to check if you accept cookies  
  
JEB2

| 

This ADTECH cookie is the ad server’s anonymous unique user ID, used for example to control the number of ads seen by a user.

ADTECH uses cookies to store the following non-person-related data:

  * Browser type (such as Chrome 9.x)
  * Operating system (such as Windows 7)
  * Date and time at which a specific banner was delivered

When collecting or storing data, ADTECH conforms with the data protection law and fulfils the regulations of the Privacy Preferences Projects (P3P), that are determined by the World Wide Web group.  
  
Doubleclick.net

|   
  
ID

| 

We use this Google DoubleClick cookie to measure the effectiveness of its online marketing campaigns. Google provides options for opting out of the DoubleClick cookie.  
  
Google.com

|   
| 

Google uses cookies, like the PREF, NID, and SID cookies, to help customise ads on Google properties, like Google Search. For example, they use such cookies to remember your most recent searches, your previous interactions with an advertiser’s ads or search results, and your visits to an advertiser’s website. This helps them to show you customised ads on Google.  
  
Twitter.com

|   
  
pid, metrics_token

| 

These cookies are created by Twitter. In this case they are present because a Twitter widget or button is being used on the website.  
  
Facebook.com

|   
| 

These cookies are created by Facebook. In this case they are present because a Facebook widget or button is being used on the website.  
  
Cookies set by third party companies

SAFC.com

|   
---|---  
  
_utma, _utmb, _utmc, _utmz

| 

Cookies related to Google Analytics which facilitate tracking information about how the website is being used e.g. number of users.  
  
[ASP.NET](http://asp.net/) SessionID

| 

This cookie is used to create a unique session identifier (a random number specific just to your session on the website) so that we can store the data regarding your session. This cookie expires at the end of your session (when you leave the website) and will be removed when you close your browser.
